（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）龐煖(ほうけん)に襲われた飛信(ひしん)隊は
散り散りに敗走した
After being attacked by Pang Nuan, the Feixin Unit fled in all directions.
Meanwhile, the survivors of the Gan Yang Army were picked up by the Lu Wuwei Army.
一方 干央(かんおう)軍の生き残った兵は
録嗚未(ろくおみ)軍に拾われた
After one night, the Feixin Unit was cut in half to a total of 36 people, including 13 Wuchang.
一夜が明け…
伍長(ごちょう)13人を含む計36人
半分以下となった飛信隊は―
傷の塞がらぬまま 再び
武器を手に歩き始めたのである
With their wounds still open, they took up their weapons once again and began to walk.
そして…
And...
（沛浪(はいろう)）間違いねえ　秦国(しんこく)の旗だ
No doubt about it. That's the State of Qin flag.
（沛浪）散った兵を集めてるんだ
They're gathering together the scattered troops. Let's go, Captain.
行ってみようぜ 隊長
（信(しん)）よし
Okay.
（渕(えん)）味方です！
（信）違う
Allies!
No... They're...
あいつらは… 秦国軍じゃねえ！
not the Qin Army!
（渉孟(しょうもう)）
フフフッ… 早速 引っ掛かったか
Looks like we've ensnared some already.
秦国の猿は全滅ね！
Let's wipe out these State of Qin monkeys!
Run!
逃げろ！
騎馬が登れない崖によじ登れ！
Claw your way up those cliffs, their horses can't climb them!
急げ！ ケガ人を先に！
Hurry! Wounded first!
（尾平(びへい)）何だ？ この地響きは
（沛浪）後ろだ！
What's causing this tremor?!
Behind us!
（松左(しょうさ)）後ろから騎馬の大軍が！
There's an army of mounted soldiers coming from behind us!
（尾平）あれも趙国(ちょうこく)軍かよ？
Is that the State of Zhao Army, too?!
いや あれは―
No, that's...
王騎(おうき)将軍！
General Wang Qi!
ついに
俺たちの大将が出陣したんだ！
Our Great General has finally taken to the field!
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）時は紀元前 春秋戦国時代
The setting is before the common era, in the Spring and Autumn Warring States Period.
名もなき存在から
百人隊の将にまでなった少年 信は
Xin, the boy that came from obscurity to become the general of a Hundred-Man Unit
激戦の真っただ中で活躍を続け
秦国軍を優勢に導いた
continued to prove himself in the height of battle and led the State of Qin Army to dominance.
だが今
ついに姿を現した敵の総大将は―
But now the enemy Supreme Commander has finally shown himself
想像を絶する存在であった
and is a being beyond imagination.
The name of that man, whom is linked by fate to Wang Qi, is Pang Nuan.
王騎との因縁を持つという
その男の名は“龐煖”
The state of the war has finally started to really shake up.
戦局は いよいよ 大きく動きだす
Presented by Anime-Destiny
itsumo yori hayaku kietetta hoshi zora ni
いつもより早く消えてった星空に
In a starry sky that disappeared faster than it ever has
Translation
kewl0210
kusanariatta deai wa
重なり合った出会いは
the many piled up meetings we've had
Editing
jagman1x3
ore wo nomikonde iku
俺を呑み込んでいく
swallow me.
kono yume wa kudakenai
この夢は砕けない
This dream cannot be broken.
Timing
rtrs
sabitsukaseta kyoufushin
錆びつかせた恐怖心
Among this rusted fear in my heart
yuragu fuan no naka de
揺らぐ不安の中で
and the anxiety that makes me waver
Typesetting
kewl0210
ame wo saegiru shinjitsu
雨を遮る信実
is a truth that interrupts the rain.
dare ni mo ubaeyashinai
誰にも奪えやしない
No one can take it away,
Karaoke
kewl0210
FZeroWing
onaji keshiki ni hisonda puraido
同じ景色にひそんだプライド
our pride that lurks in the same landscape.
Encode
max80
itsuka kitto kanau ima mo mieru kibou fortitude
いつかきっと叶う 今も見える希望 fortitude
The fortuitous desire I have will definitely come true one day.
yowasa wo sute wa shinai
弱さを捨てはしない
We won't throw away our weaknesses,
oretachi no kienai shiin
俺達の消えないシーン
those are scenes that won't disappear.
furenzokusen no youni hashiru kibou unbreakable heart
不連続線の様に走る希望 unbreakable heart
My desire in my unbreakable heart runs like a discontinuous line.
I knew at the start that there's no end.
QC
Mistral[sA]
I've made up my mind, right now it's the time to take the first step.
Distro
kokus
Kittie
prefix-
Now's the only time.
～♪
Wang Qi Takes to the Field!
（王騎）ンフフッ…
I estimated that foolish behavior like that to be She Meng's doing.
あんなおバカなマネをするのは
渉孟辺りと踏んでましたが
It seems I was right.
そのとおりでしたねえ
（騰）はっ！ おバカの発想です
Yes, sir. Quite a foolish idea!
It seems that he is not the one who beat the 4th Army, but oh well.
（王騎）第４軍をやってくれたのは
彼ではないようですが
しかたありません
I will take this sadness we have suffered
我々が受けた この悲しみ…
とりあえずは ここで 渉孟さんに
受け止めていただきましょう
and give it to Mr. She Meng for the moment.
General Wang Qi went out in front!
（渕）王騎将軍が前に出た！
The Mystery Bird of Qin, Wang Qi...
（渉孟）“秦国の怪鳥” 王騎
この日をどれほど待ち望んだことか
How I have longed for this day...
王騎！
Wang Qi!
He's already one of the legendary Six Great Generals.
もはや伝説の六大将軍
その実力を疑う余地はない
There's no room for doubting his power.
しかし
その時代に私はいなかったよ
But I wasn't around in that age...
皆 思い知るがいい
I'll teach everyone now...
that I am a monster that even surpasses the Six Great Generals!
この私が 六大将軍を
超えるバケモノだということを
And now, I will control every battlefield on the face of China!
これからは この私が
中華全土の戦場に君臨する！
王騎ーっ！
Wang Qi!
渉孟… 貴様ごとき
我らの殿の足元にも及ばぬ
She Meng... Someone like you does not even reach the feet of my lord.
ンフッ…
Th-That is... the power of our... Supreme Commander...
（渕）
あ… あれが 我らが総大将の力…
（崇原(すうげん)）見ろ！ 敵が ひいていく
Look! The enemy is retreating!
（趙兵）ひけ！ ひけー！
Retreat! Retreat!
（王騎）一夜にして 半分以下に
なってしまいましたねえ 飛信隊は
So the Feixin Unit was cut in half overnight, was it...?
つらいですか？ 童 信
Is it frustrating, Youngster Xin?
I'm trying not to think too hard about it right now.
今は 深く考えねえようにしてる
そうしねえと―
If I do, I feel like I'll end up crouching down
この場に うずくまって
足が前に出せねえ気がするんだ
and won't be able to make my feet move forward.
（信）だけど 死んだヤツらは
そんなこと望んでねえ 絶対に
But the guys that died definitely wouldn't want that. I know it.
だから 今は この36人で
どうやって戦って 武功を上げるか
So... The only thing I can think about is how I can fight with these 36
それしか考えてねえ
to render more achievements.
ココココッ… せっかく
励ましてやろうと思ったのに
I thought I would finally give you a compliment,
but it seems that there is no need for it, is there, Teng?
その必要はなさそうですねえ 騰
（騰）はっ！ つまらぬガキです
Yes, sir. He is a boring kid.
Your posture isn't bad, Youngster Xin.
あなたの姿勢は
悪くないですよ 童 信
（王騎）
武将への道は 犠牲の道です
The path to military general is a path of sacrifice.
Every time they overcome them, people and units become bigger and stronger.
そこを乗り越える度に 人も隊も
より強く 大きくなるのです
いや そうならねばなりません
No, they must do so.
（王騎）あなたたちを“飛信隊”と
名付けた甲斐(かい)がありました
There was value in me giving you the name Feixin Unit.
Now then, I must be going.
それでは 行きますよ
決戦が近づいています
The decisive battle is drawing near.
（趙兵）趙荘(ちょうそう)さま！
龐煖さまが ご帰還なされました
Lord Zhao Zhuang!
Lord Pang Nuan has returned!
More than anything, I am glad you are safe.
（趙荘）ご無事で何よりでした
（龐煖）王騎が出たかと思い
勝手をした　許せ
I acted on my own because I thought Wang Qi may have appeared.
Forgive me.
（趙荘）
いえ　龐煖さまがご無事であれば
作戦には何ら支障はありません
No, as long as you are all right, Lord Pang Nuan,
there has been no impediment to the battle strategy.
しかし
どうか今後は 私に ひと言 お声を
But, if possible, please give me a word of warning about such a thing in the future.
Otherwise, I fear everything could become spoiled.
さもなくば 全てが
台なしになるおそれがあります
案ずるな　分かっている
Do not be concerned. I understand.
Lord Zhao Zhuang!
（伝令）趙荘さま！
後方に のろしが上がっております
A signal fire has been raised in the rear!
It's a signal that Lord She Meng has been killed in battle!
（伝令）渉孟さまの討ち死にを
知らせる のろしです
What?! She Meng was killed?!
なに？ 渉孟が討ち死にだと？
（伝令）は… はい
それに のろしは もう１本
Y-Yes sir.
And there was a second signal!
王騎の出現を知らせる のろしです
One signifying that Wang Qi has appeared!
ハッ… ついに来たか 王騎！
So you've finally come, Wang Qi?!
結果的に 龐煖さまの夜襲が―
As a result of Lord Pang Nuan's night attack
that highly vigilant man was brought into the mountains?
警戒心の強いヤツを
山に入らせたのか
The loss of She Meng is a painful blow,
渉孟を失ったことは痛手だが
この趙国軍にとって致命傷ではない
but it is not a fatal blow for the State of Zhao Army.
Zhao Army
Headquarters
Wang Qi
（趙荘）ここから
それぞれの軍が―
Now, each of our armies will attack the State of Qin Army with the goal of stopping their movement.
秦国の各軍を捕まえ
足止めを図る
If the isolated Wang Qi Army gets close to this headquarters...
その結果
孤立した王騎軍が―
この本陣を
追ってくれば…
Zhao Army
Headquarters
Wang Qi
趙国軍が勝つ！ フフフッ…
the State of Zhao Army will be victorious!
（蒙武(もうぶ)）あれがヤツらの本陣か
（隆国(りゅうこく)）間違いありません
So that's their headquarters...?
Without a hint of uncertainty.
Your said your name was Long Guo, isn't it?
（蒙武）貴様 隆国といったな？
見事な道案内だった
You were a magnificent guide.
ありがとうございます
今ならば 敵は油断しております
Thank you, sir.
Right now, the enemy has their guard down.
味方の軍を
背後に回したいと思いますが
I think it would be prudent for you to bring your army around to their rear, sir...
要らぬ　ここまで近づけば
もはや逃がさぬ！
No need.
After we've gotten this far
they can no longer escape!
（蒙武）行くぞ！
（鬨(とき)の声）
Let's go!
（貂(てん)）のろしが上がっている
何かあったのかな？
There are signal flares burning...
Ya think something happened?
（蒙毅(もうき)）僕は部外者だから
どっちの軍のものかも分からない
I'm an outsider, so I can't even tell whose army's those are,
ただ 山あいの戦いは
僕の想像以上に厳しい
but I'm sure the battle going on in the mountains is more fierce than anything we could imagine.
例えば
どこにいるか分からない友軍に―
For example, they're in a state where the only way for them to communicate something to scattered friendly troops,
何かを伝えるには
のろし以外に手はない
is to use smoke signals.
しかし 逆に
敵に自分の位置を知られてしまう
But that also has the adverse effect of letting the enemy know their position.
Unless they have a very important reason to do so, they won't use those.
（蒙毅）
よほど大きな理由がないかぎり
あれは上げられない
A very important reason...
（貂）よほど大きな理由…
（李牧(りぼく)）のろしのほかにも
伝達手段はあるみたいですよ
There do seem to be means of communication besides smoke signals.
何ですか？ 李牧どの
What are they, Lord Li Mu?
ハッ… 旗…
Flags.
The flags at the State of QIn Army Headquarters have changed since early this morning.
（李牧）秦国本陣の旗が
早朝とは変わっています
それって どういうこと？
What's that mean?
（李牧）
旗は 色や配置の組み合わせで
細やかな情報を送れますからねえ
You see, the combination of the flags' colors and locations
can send complicated information.
まあ しかし 旗には 見える範囲が
狭いという欠点もありますけど
However, the disadvantage of that is the limited range for where you can see the flags.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）旗の意味するところ
The meaning of the flags:
それは“王騎が山中に
入った”という知らせであった
they are a notification that Wang Qi has entered the mountains.
そして 王騎のもとにも…
And at Wang Qi's location...
Take a look, Teng.
（王騎）騰 ご覧なさい
It's a smoke signal that's telling us the location of the State of Zhao headquarters.
趙国本陣の場所を
知らせる のろしです
恐らく隆国でしょう
（騰）はっ！ さすが隆国です
Most likely it's Long Guo.
Yes, sir. Just what I'd expect from Long Guo.
But it's rising from an area much deeper in than I expected.
しかし
思った以上に奥深くから上がった
It seems that rather than Long Guo being late, Zhao Zhuang's pulling was early.
隆国が遅かったというより
趙荘のひきが早かったようですねえ
はっ！ なかなかの策士です
Yes, sir. He is quite the tactician.
The one directing the headquarters is Zhao Zhuang of course,
本陣の指揮を執るのは
もちろん趙荘なのでしょうが
but if perhaps Pang Nuan is among them...
もし
そこに龐煖が絡んでくるとしたら…
さすがに先が読みづらいですねえ
the future will indeed be hard to predict.
With things in this state, I'm worried for Meng Wu.
（王騎）こうなると
少々 蒙武が気がかりです
恐らく
もう戦闘は始まっているでしょう
His battle is likely to have already started.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
王騎の予想どおり そのころ―
Just as Wang Qi predicted, at that moment
the battle between the Zhao Zhuang Army and the Meng Wu and the Long Guo Armies have turned into huge melee.
趙荘軍 対 蒙武 隆国軍の戦いは
大混戦となっていた
In the battle's opening, the Meng Wu and Long Guo Armies that raided their enemy wielded great power,
序盤こそ 急襲した蒙武 隆国軍が
猛威を振るったが
but before the Zhao Zhuang Army's clever counterattack,
趙荘軍の巧みな迎撃の前に
勢いを止められ
their momentum was halted and both armies struggled for supremacy.
両軍の力は拮抗(きっこう)した
だが それでも 蒙武を先頭に―
However, with Meng Wu at the lead,
the Meng Wu and Long Guo Armies were able to slowly push back the Zhao Zhuang Army.
蒙武 隆国軍が
徐々に趙荘軍を押し込んでいった
This is a report to the Meng Wu and Long Guo Armies!
蒙武軍 隆国軍に告ぐ！
あの長髪の大男が龐煖だ！
That long-haired man is Pang Nuan!
The Zhao Army Supreme Commander has brazenly entered come onto the field!
（隆国）
趙国軍総大将がノコノコ現れたぞ！
囲んで 首を取れ！
Surround him and take his head!
So as I thought, that man is Pang Nuan?
やはり あの男が龐煖か
どうりで ただ者ではないと思った
Indeed, I did not think he would be an ordinary man...
（蒙武）これほど強烈な
武のにおいのする男は初めてだ
This is the first time I've met a man who exudes such an intense smell of battle.
ハッ… この俺が冷や汗だと？
I'm breaking out into a cold sweat?!
面白い！
Interesting!
ハアーッ！
ドリャー！
な… なに？
Wh-What?!
に… 逃げた
H-He ran?!
おのれ 貴様！
まさか この俺では力不足とでも？
You bastard...
Do you perhaps think that I am lacking in power...?
逃げられると思うか！
（兵士）蒙武さまに続け！
Do not expect to get away!
Follow Lord Meng Wu!
いや 何だ？ 何かが おかしい
No... What is this...?
Something is odd.
だが 龐煖を
討つ好機であることには違いない
However, this is undoubtedly a good opportunity to slay Pang Nuan.
（趙荘）網に掛かった魚は違ったが
これは これでいい
Not quite like a fish caught in a net,
but this will do for our purposes.
（副官）まさかヤツらも 総大将を
囮(おとり)に使ったとは思いますまい
I highly doubt they would expect us to use our own Supreme Commander as a decoy.
Wang Qi... In the end, you will be forced to show yourself.
王騎よ… 結局
貴様は出てこざるをえなくなる
No, this is bad!
ここはマズイ　明らかにワナだ
This is clearly a trap!
General Meng Wu!
蒙武将軍… オッ？
Lord!
（兵士）殿！
（隆国）蒙武将軍！
General Meng Wu!
（蒙武）被害は？
The damage?
ざっと見積もっても
半分は やられたかと
Just at an estimate, half were beaten.
半分か… 十分だ　行くぞ
（隆国）お待ちください
Half, eh...?
We still have plenty. Let's go.
Please wait!
敵の軍師 趙荘は 龐煖をエサにして
将軍を釣ろうとしている
The enemy strategist Zhao Zhuang
is trying to lure you in with Pang Nuan as bait!
ここは いったん引き返して
立て直しを図るべきです
We should make a temporary retreat and seek to regroup!
そこが大きな間違いだ
That would be a big mistake.
No strategy can stop me!
策で この俺は止められぬわ！
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）蒙武が 趙荘のワナに
かかった ちょうど そのころ
Just as Meng Wu was falling for Zhao Zhuang's trap,
Wang Qi split up his mounted unit and infantry unit.
王騎は 騎馬隊と歩兵隊を分離させ
The mounted unit took detour paths that the horses could travel on.
騎馬隊は 馬の走れる道を探り 迂回(うかい)
Foot Soldiers
Mounted Soldiers
歩兵は その機動性を生かして―
The foot soldiers made use of their maneuverability
直線的に ほぼ同じ速さで
趙国軍本陣 目がけて疾走していた
and sprinted their way in a straight line,
going at about the same speed towards the State of Zhao Army headquarters.
（信）尾平 崇原
お前ら あんまりムリするな
Wei Ping, Chong Yuan, don't push yourselves too hard.
“ついてこられねえヤツは
離脱してかまわねえ”って―
General Wang Qi said he doesn't mind if people who can't keep up break away from the group.
王騎将軍が言ってた
（尾平）
バカ言ってんじゃねえよ 信
Don't talk nonsense, Xin!
ここまで来て
休んで寝てろってのか？
You want us to take a break and sleep after coming this far?
Y-You've got to be joking.
じょ… 冗談じゃねえ　俺は行くぞ
もう戦えねえかもしんねえが
I'm going.
I might not be able to fight anymore, but...
この目で最後まで見届けるんだ
この戦をな！
I want to see this through to the end with my own eyes!
This war!
He's right.
（崇原）そういうことだ
（松左）しかし まあ
こんなに飛ばしていいもんかねえ
But, man...
Is it really a good idea for us to be running so fast?
無防備すぎだろう
We're far too defenseless.
敵の伏兵にでも会ったら
俺たち メチャクチャやられっぞ
If we ran into an enemy ambush, we would get beat in a second.
ハハッ…
将軍が急いでるのは分かるが
I can understand why the general's rushing, but I don't know about us.
これは ちょっとないぜ
（羌瘣(きょうかい)）敵がいないということが
分かっているんだ 王騎将軍には
General Wang Qi knows that there are no enemies here.
こんな山の中で
どうして分かるんだ？
How can he tell that out here in the mountains?
I don't know that much.
（羌瘣）そこまでは知らん
As blunt as always, our Vice General.
相変わらず ぶっきらぼうだねえ
ウチの副将は
（羌瘣）うるさい　さっさと走れ
（松左）へいへい
Shut up, hurry up and get running.
Sure, sure.
Just as Qiang Lei said,
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）羌瘣の言葉どおり―
Wang Qi knew that the State of Zhao Army would not be at his destination.
王騎は 行き先に
趙国軍がいないことを知っていた
The reason was, as one would expect, the flags.
理由は やはり旗だ
王騎は 進みながらも 時折
旗を秦国本陣に向けて掲げている
As Wang Qi moved forward flags would occasionally be raised towards the direction of the State of Qin headquarters.
それは 山あいに散った
各軍長たちへの知らせであった
That was a signal to each army combat commander scattered throughout the mountains.
The subordinates that remained at the headquarters in turn raised the same flags at the headquarters.
本陣に残っている配下たちは―
その知らせを
そのまま本陣の旗で掲げる
By seeing those, the commanders could send information back and forth.
各所の軍長は
それを見ることで―
情報のやり取りを
行っていたのである
Of course, Wang Qi was also notified of the commanders signals via the headquarters.
無論 逆に軍長たちの知らせも
本陣を通して 王騎に届いた
In other words, as long as he was within view of the headquarters,
つまり
本陣が見える位置にいるかぎり―
Zhao Zhuang
Meng Wu
Long Guo
Wan Ji
Engaged in Battle
Lu Wuwei
Wang Qi
Li Hai
Gonsung Long
Battling Close By
Tong Jin
Lin Fang
王騎は 秦国 趙国 全軍の
配置と状態を把握していたのである
Wang Qi could grasp the arrangement and status of the State of Qin and State of Zhao.
ただし
趙国本陣に接触したであろう―
However, they did not know the condition
蒙武 隆国軍の動静は
分からなかった
of the Meng Wu and Long Guo Armies that had made contact with State of Zhao Headquarters.
Zhao Zhuang
Meng Wu
Long Guo
両軍からの
王騎への返答がないからだ
That is because both armies gave no reply to Wang Qi.
故に 王騎は 進軍の足を更に速めた
Therefore, Wang Qi's advanced was quickened even further.
また旗の配置が変わりましたねえ
Looks like the positions of the flags changed again.
戦況が動いているということですね
（李牧）そういうことです
That means the state of battle is changing, doesn't it?
Yep, it does.
Kaine.
（貂）カイネ
（カイネ）うん？
はい 食べ物　カイネの分
Here, some food.
This is your share.
おいしいですねえ
（蒙毅）はい
Tasty, isn't it?
Yes.
（カイネ）おう
（貂）あっ…
Sure.
フゥ…
（貂）カイネって…
（カイネ）うん？
Kaine.
やっぱり 女だよね？
（カイネ）当たり前だ
I guess you're a woman, huh?
Obviously.
だよね！ いや でも その…
女って感じがしないから―
Yeah, totally.
Uh, but, um...
You don't really give off the sensation of a girl, so I thought maybe you were a man...
もしかしたら男かと…
（カイネ）なに？
What?!
（カイネ）ああ！ なんだ お前も…
What? You're also a wo-
そうか… まあ このご時世―
I see.
Well, in this era
男装して生き抜く女は
珍しくないっちゃない
it's not uncommon for woman to survive by disguising themselves as men.
…で？ 調子に乗って 男に交じって
軍師にでもなろうと？
So, are you pushing your luck and mixing in with men to try to become a strategist or something?
（カイネ）違うのか？
Is that not it?
まだ分かんねえ
I still don't know...
I just kinda feel like... if I don't do something, I'll get left behind.
（貂）ただ漠然と 何かしなきゃ
取り残されるって思って
どうすればいいか
分かんなかったけど
Though I really don't know what I should do.
ここに来て
それが少し見えた気がするんだ
After coming here, I kinda feel like I could see that a little...
Quit thinking like that.
そんな考えなら やめとけ
（貂）えっ？
お前は何も分かっていない
You don't understand anything.
軍師になろうとするなら
その本質を理解しなければいけない
If you do intend on becoming a strategist,
you have to understand the true nature of that.
本質？
（カイネ）そうだ　軍師とは―
True nature?
That's right.
Being a strategist is far more painful and difficult than being a soldier that sees bloodshed right in front of him.
前線で血を流す兵士よりも
はるかに苦しく つらいもの
And...
そして…
it's even more terrifying.
（カイネ）恐ろしいものだ
（副官）趙荘さま 来ました
（趙荘）うん？
Lord Zhao Zhuang, they've come.
It's the Wang Qi Army!
（副官）王騎軍です
あれが趙国本陣…
That's the State of Zhao headquarters...
（渕）しかし 一体…
（信）ああ…
But what on earth...
Yeah...
（信）敵がいねえじゃねえか！
There are no enemies here!
これでいい
This is fine.
For now, we'll stop right here.
しばし この場にとどまり―
情報を収集しましょう
（騰）はっ！
Let's gather information.
Yes, sir!
Report! Report!
（伝令）報告！ 報告！
（士官１）
バカな！ ワナに掛かり―
That's insane!
He was caught in a trap and lost half his army, but he followed in deeper?!
軍の半数を失いながら
深追いしただと？
How could he do this, and with Long Guo with him?!
隆国がついていながら
なんということだ！
No, he had no choice but to keep pursuing.
（士官２）いや 追跡は致し方ない
総大将が目の前にいるなら
蒙武でなくても 追うだろう
With the Supreme Commander in front of his eyes,
any general would follow him.
それより 問題は 消えた趙荘の軍だ
But more pressing is the disappearance of Zhao Zhuang.
防衛柵を施したこの本陣を捨てて
ヤツらは どこに行ったんだ？
They abandoned this headquarters with defensive fences set up.
Where would they have gone?
蒙武のとどめを刺しに行ったのです
（士官２）殿…
They went to finish off Meng Wu.
My lord...
（王騎）恐らく趙荘は―
Most likely, Zhao Zhuang...
Zhao Headquarters
多数の部隊を
蒙武の行く道に―
has positioned several units to ambush Meng Wu on his path.
伏兵として配置し
To carve away at his army little by little.
少しずつ
その軍を削り取る
And once it's been thinned out, the main army would come around the bend and finish them off.
そして
やせ細ったところを
回り込んだ本隊で―
討ち果たす
つもりでしょう
So if we follow the Zhao Zhuang Army,
（士官１）
すると 趙荘軍を追えば―
おのずと
蒙武軍を助けに行けるということか
we'll naturally be able to come to the aid of the Meng Wu Army, yes?
But if we continue on this path, we'll lose track of our own main army.
（士官２）しかし この先に進めば
我々は 我が軍の本陣を見失う
Not only that, but we'll lose sight of this full map of this wide battlefield.
それは ひいては この広い戦場の
全体図を見失うということだ
（王騎）致し方ないでしょう
（士官たち）ハッ…
There is no choice, is there?
この私を 秦国本陣の
見えない所まで おびき出す
They're luring us to a place where I can't see the State of Qin headquarters.
それが 趙荘の策でしょうから
That is Zhao Zhuang's plan.
この地に とどまっていても
向こうは動きません
Even if I remain here, their armies will not move.
（王騎）
それに 蒙武が今 受けているワナは
And the trap that Meng Wu is falling into
is certain to have a secret plan meant to defeat me.
趙荘が私を討つために
仕掛けていた秘策のはず
下手をすれば 蒙武は
ここで命を落としてしまいます
If we are careless, Meng Wu will lose his life here.
皆さん 出陣です！
Everyone, let's take to the field!
何人 落ちた？
（兵士）2,000ほど
How many men did we lose?
Approximately 2,000!
おのれ！
Bastard!
Pang Nuan!
龐煖！
やれ！ 蒙武将軍！
Do it, General Meng Wu!
やりましたな 蒙武将軍
You really did it, General Meng Wu!
（蒙武）違う
（隆国）えっ？
No.
これは龐煖ではない　ニセモノだ
（隆国）な… なんと…
This man is not Pang Nuan.
He is a fake.
Wh-What?!
皆 気をつけろ　来るぞ
Everyone, be careful.
They're coming.
（政(せい)）夜戦だと？
A night attack?!
（昌平君(しょうへいくん)）先ほど
上がった のろしでは そのように
According to a smoke signal that was recently raised, it seems so...
（昌平君）
それに 龐煖が現れたようです
And also... it seems Pang Nuan appeared.
Pang Nuan?!
（昌文君）龐煖？ しかし なぜ…
But why?!
そもそも 夜戦など
大軍が行うべき策ではございません
The idea of a night attack is not the kind of plan a large army should be enacting.
恐らく 突発的な何かが起きたかと
It's probable that something unexpected occurred.
（昌文君）それが龐煖の出現か
（昌平君）はい
And that is the appearance of Pang Nuan?!
Yes.
A few days ago, you said about Pang Nuan
先日 お前は 龐煖のことを―
“あれは武将ではない
完全なる個 武の結晶”
"He is not a military general. He is a complete army. A manifestation of war."
Did you not?
そう評したな？
（昌文君）はっ！
Yes.
そのような男に
総大将が務まるものだろうか
Would such a man be hired as a Supreme Commander?
しかし
現に龐煖は 総大将として戦場に…
But currently, Pang Nuan is on the battlefield as acting Supreme Commander.
This war is odd.
この戦は奇妙だ
いや あるいは…
No!
Perhaps...
（扉の開く音）
（役人）大王さま！
Your highness!
What's wrong?
（昌文君）どうした？
（役人）緊急事態です
It's an emergency situation!
That is...
あれは…
昌文君 行くぞ
（昌文君）はっ！
Changwenjun, let's go.
Yes, my king.
久々の再会は うれしいが
急に どうしたというのだ？
I'm delighted to see you again after so long, but...
why arrive so suddenly?
Yang Duan He?
（楊端和）元気そうだな 秦王 政
You seem healthy, Qin King Zheng.
大変なときに すまないが
Sorry for coming at such a critical time, but...
there is something concerning the current war
こたびの戦に関して どうしても
お前に伝えねばならぬことがあり
that I absolutely must tell you, and so I came here.
訪ねて来たのだ
（政）伝えねばならぬこと？
Something you must tell me?
赤き　血潮
akaki chishio
Crimson blood flowing...
この鼓動は　野望なのか
kono kodou wa yabou na no ka
Is this racing pulse ambition?
幼き日　誓った
osanaki hi chigatta
Even now, I do not waver
夢は今も　揺るがない
yume wa ima mo yuru ga nai
from that dream I dedicated myself to in my youth.
命が燃える
inochi ga moeru
My life burns bright.
Ｎｅｖｅｒ　Ｅｎｄｉｎｇ　Ｓｏｕｌ　情熱よ
Never Ending Soul jounetsu yo
Never Ending Soul of passion,
導け　天地を拓け
michibike tenchi wo hirake
guide me and open the path to heaven.
Ｎｅｖｅｒ　Ｅｎｄｉｎｇ　Ｗｏｒｌｄ　打ち立てよう
Never Ending World uchitateyou
Let's create a Never Ending World!
永遠の絆が誇り
eien no kizuna ga hokori
Boasting an eternal bond,
おまえと夢見た世界を　この手に　掴もう
omae to yumemita sekai wo kono te ni tsukamou
you and I will grasp the world we dreamed of.
～♪
Preview
Now, shall we settle this once and for all?
（王騎）さあ！
決着をつけるとしましょうか
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）立ちこめる殺気
鬼神のほほえみに 道が開く
Shrouded in murderous intent,
the path opens to the smile of a fierce god!
Central
Performers
End
Central
Performers
Next time,
次回 “真打ち”